{"test_questions": [[{"question": "HPLC stands for", "opta": "High Pressure Liquid Chromatography", "optb": "High Performance Liquid Chromatography", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Highly Placed Liquid Chromatography", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The eluent strength is a measure of", "opta": "solvent adsorption energy", "optb": "solvent absorption energy", "optc": "solvent diffusivity", "optd": "solvent mixing index", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "HPLC methods include", "opta": "liquid/liquid (partition) chromatography", "optb": "liquid/solid (adsorption) chromatography", "optc": "ion exchange and size exclusion chromatography", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Column efficiency is measured in terms of number of plates which is", "opta": "inversely related to the square of the peak width", "optb": "directly related to the square of the peak width", "optc": "inversely related to the cube root of the peak width", "optd": "directly related to the square of the peak width", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For a typical adsorbent such as silica gel, the most popular pore diameters are", "opta": "10 and 50 A\u00b0", "optb": "60 and 100 A\u00b0", "optc": "100 and 150 A\u00b0", "optd": "150 and 200 A\u00b0", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An isocratic elution in HPLC is one in which the composition of the solvent", "opta": "remains constant", "optb": "changes continuously", "optc": "changes in a series of steps", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In reversed phase HPLC, there is a", "opta": "non polar solvent/polar column", "optb": "polar solvent/non-polar column", "optc": "non polar solvent/non-polar column", "optd": "any of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements is true for a refractive index detector in HPLC?", "opta": "It is more sensitive than a UV detector", "optb": "It can only be used for isocratic elutions", "optc": "It does not respond to many solutes", "optd": "none of above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A gradient elution in HPLC is one in which the composition of the solvent", "opta": "remains constant", "optb": "is changed continuously or in a series of steps", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An eluotropic series", "opta": "ranks solvents by their relative abilities to displace solutes from a given absorbent", "optb": "ranks column packing material by their relative abilities to retain solutes on the column", "optc": "is a measure of the solvent adsorption energy", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Dwell volume is defined as", "opta": "the volume of solvent contained in a liquid chromatographic column", "optb": "the time required for the gradient to reach the column", "optc": "the volume of the column between the point at which solvents are mixed and the beginning of the column", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Void volume refers to the", "opta": "total volume of eluent in the column the remainder being taken up by the packing material", "optb": "the volume of solvent contained in a liquid chromatographic column", "optc": "the time required for the gradient to reach the column", "optd": "the volume of the column between the point at which solvents are mixed and the beginning of the column", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In normal phase HPLC, there is a", "opta": "non polar solvent/polar column", "optb": "polar solvent/non-polar column", "optc": "non polar solvent/non-polar column", "optd": "any of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following(s) is/are the advantage of HPLC over traditional LPLC (low-pressure liquid chromatography)?", "opta": "Greater sensitivity and reusable columns", "optb": "Ideal for ionic species and large molecules", "optc": "Sample recovery", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which can be used as a mobile phase in HPLC applications?", "opta": "Any compound with solubility in liquid", "optb": "Any compound with limited solubility in liquid", "optc": "Any compound with non-solubility in liquid", "optd": "Any of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}